SimToolkit Hierarchy
===============

Service		org.ofono
Interface	org.ofono.SimToolkit
Object path	[variable prefix]/{modem0,modem1,...}

Methods		dict GetProperties()

			Returns properties for the SimToolkit object.  See the
			properties section for available properties.

		void SelectItem(byte item, object agent)

			Selects an item from the main menu, thus triggering
			a new user session.  The agent parameter specifies
			a new agent to be used for the duration of the
			user session.

			Possible Errors: [service].Error.InProgress
					 [service].Error.NotSupported
					 [service].Error.InvalidArguments
					 [service].Error.InvalidFormat
					 [service].Error.Failed

		void RegisterAgent(object path)

			Registers a default agent to be used for SIM initiated
			actions such as Display Text, Get Inkey or Get Input.
			These can typically occur when a special SMS is
			received and might not involve interaction from the
			user.

			Possible Errors: [service].Error.InProgress
					 [service].Error.InvalidArguments
					 [service].Error.InvalidFormat
					 [service].Error.Failed

		void UnregisterAgent(object path)

			Unregisters the default agent.  If no agent is
			registered then unsolicited commands from the SIM
			are rejected.

			Possible Errors: [service].Error.InvalidArguments
					 [service].Error.Failed

Signals		PropertyChanged(string property, variant value)

			Signal is emitted whenever a property has changed.
			The new value is passed as the signal argument.

Properties	string IdleModeText [readonly]

			Contains the text to be used when the home screen is
			idle.  This text is set by the SIM and can change
			at any time.

		byte IdleModeIcon [readonly]

			Contains the identifier of the icon accompanying
			the idle mode text.

		array{struct{string, byte}} MainMenu [readonly]

			Contains the items that make up the main menu.  This
			is populated by the SIM when it sends the Setup Menu
			Proactive Command.  The main menu is always available,
			but its contents can be changed at any time.  Each
			item contains the item label and icon identifier.

		string MainMenuTitle [readonly]

			Contains the title of the main menu.

		string MainMenuIcon [readonly]

			Contains the identifier of the icon for the main menu.
